femmefrugality.com 2018-07-31

# Privacy Policy & Disclosures | Femme Frugality

## General Disclaimer

This blog is written for entertainment purposes only. I am not a financial professional, therefore readers are advised to do their own, thorough research or seek the help of a financial professional before making any financial or purchasing decisions. The information that is found here are personal opinions and/or the opinions of readers and should not be taken as financial advice.  Femme Frugality does not make any representations as to the accuracy or suitability of the claims made here. Femme Frugality does not assume any liability in regard to financial results based on the use of information provided on femmefrugality.com.

## Advertising and Sponsored Content

In accordance with FTC guidelines, the owner of Femme Frugality discloses that we may have a financial relationship with companies mentioned on femmefrugality.com. Femme Frugality may be compensated at times by third party companies that are mentioned either in advertisements, product reviews or affiliate programs.

All information on Femme Frugality should be considered as information or entertainment. We provide our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on the topics and products we review. The views and opinions expressed are purely the authors’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

Information that you find on femmefrugality.com can change. While we do our best to make sure all information is up to date, we cannot guarantee that all of the time.

Femme Frugality is not responsible for the content or claims of articles written by outside parties.

## Privacy Policy

_This privacy policy has been compiled to better serve those who are concerned with how their ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is being used online. PII, as used in US privacy law and information security, is information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact, or locate a single person, or to identify an individual in context. Please read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your Personally Identifiable Information in accordance with our website._

**What personal information do we collect from the people that visit our blog?**

When registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your email address or other details to help you with your experience.

**When do we collect information?**

We collect information from you when you subscribe to a newsletter or enter information on our site.

**How do we use your information?**

We may use the information we collect from you when you register, make a purchase, sign up for our newsletter, respond to a survey or marketing communication, surf the website, or use certain other site features in the following ways:

• To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature.

• To send periodic emails regarding content.

**How do we protect visitor information?**

We use regular Malware Scanning, but do not use vulnerability scanning and/or scanning to PCI standards because we do not handle credit cards on this site or collect credit card information.

**We do not use an SSL certificate**

We do not need an SSL because personally identifiable information is not stored here. Subscribers submit identifiable information through a double opt-in system, and the information is held on the service provider’s (Mail Chimp’s) server, which does have an SSL certificate.

**Do we use ‘cookies’?**

Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. For instance, we use cookies to help us understand your preferences based on previous or current site activity, which enables us to provide you with improved services. We also use cookies to help us compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future.

We use cookies to compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interactions in order to offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may also use trusted third party services that track this information on our behalf.

You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies. You do this through your browser (like Internet Explorer) settings. Each browser is a little different, so look at your browser’s Help menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.

**Third Party Disclosure**

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information unless we provide you with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**Google**

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by [Google’s Advertising Principles](https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en). They are put in place to provide a positive experience for users.

We use Google AdSense Advertising on our website.

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy.

We have implemented the following:

• Google Display Network Impression Reporting

• Demographics and Interests Reporting

We along with third-party vendors, such as Google use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions, and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

_Opting out:_

Users can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising initiative opt out page or permanently using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act**

According to [CalOPPA](http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf) we agree to the following:

Users can visit our site anonymously

Once this privacy policy is created, we will add a link to it on our home page, or as a minimum on the first significant page after entering our website.

Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’, and can be easily be found on the page specified above.

Users will be notified of any privacy policy changes on our privacy policy page.

Users are able to change their personal information by emailing us.

**How does our site handle do not track signals?**

We honor do not track signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a Do Not Track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place.

**Does our site allow third party behavioral tracking?**

It’s also important to note that we allow third party behavioral tracking.

**COPPA (Children Online Privacy Protection Act)**

We do not specifically market to children under 13, and do not knowingly collect any information from them. If you are under the age of 13, please do not submit any personal data through this site. We encourage parents to monitor their children’s internet activity.

**Fair Information Practices**

In order to be in line with Fair Information Practices we will notify users via in site notification within 7 business days should a data breach occur.

**Contacting Us**

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us using the information below.

Femme Frugality

PO Box 8499

Pittsburgh, PA 15220

United States

femmefrugality@gmail.com

Last Edited on 2015-10-08
